

SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

### **Details**

Kingston Jamaica 18768590531 <u>bavin\_edwards@live.com</u>

### Links

LinkedIn

Portfolio

GitHub

### **Skills**

Node.js

HTML5

CSS

Redux

Git

**Typescript** 

React

JavaScript

Vue

### **Profile**

Passionate and experienced web developer with proven industry experience working in agile teams to deliver beautiful, responsive and user-friendly web applications. Experienced with creating component-based user interfaces, unit and integration testing, debugging, state management, authentication and code quality management.

# **Employment History**

### Senior Web Developer, Alessa, Kingston, Jamaica

AUGUST 2022 - PRESENT

- Hands-on research and development of the architecture and features for data analytic, and consumer-facing web platforms, which serves major financial institutions worldwide.
- Attend weekly architecture meetings to decide on implementation of future features.
- Facilitate weekly code review sessions to promote growth, great code quality, and a solid understanding of the goals of the project.
- Review pull requests from other developers to ensure code quality, testing and robustness.
- Tech stack: React, TypeScript, styled-components

### Web Developer, Alessa, Kingston, Jamaica

OCTOBER 2021 - AUGUST 2022

- Hands-on research and development of the architecture and features for data analytic, and consumer-facing web platforms, which serves major financial institutions worldwide.
- Tech stack: React, TypeScript, styled-components

#### Software Developer, Smart Mobile Solutions, Kingston, Jamaica

OCTOBER 2020 - OCTOBER 2021

- Developing Business Web and Mobile Applications using modern technologies and adhering to industry best practices.
- Created on-boarding Java SpringBoot course and accompanying assessment for new hires.
- Tech stack: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, NodeJS, SpringBoot, MongoDB, Express, PostgresQL

## **Education**

BSc General Physics, University of the West Indies, Mona, Kingston, Jamaica

AUGUST 2013 - FEBRUARY 2017

- Engineering scholarship, sophomore year
- Graduated with honors